Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): Last night he continued his attack on all forms of immigration by issuing his latest iteration of a travel ban. This time restricting and limiting the entry of nationals from 19 countries. This list flies in the face of what this country is supposed to stand for.
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): Banning a whole group of people because you disagree with the structure or the function of their often repressive governments not only lays blame in the wrong place, it creates a dangerous precedent. Barring people fleeing dangerous countries like Afghanistan, the Congo, Haiti, Sudan will only further destabilize global security and make us all less safe.
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): And it is simply insulting that even the so-called
Woman 2: exceptions that are in this bill are not thought out, they continue to be cruel. Just look at the fact that it apparently allows members of people from Afghanistan who assisted the U.S.
military to
Woman 2: come in, but it does not allow their family members.
Woman 2: how is that at all a solution to
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): the lives of the people who defended the United States in Afghanistan? We cannot abandon people. This discriminatory policy is just another attack on legal immigration and family unity and it will hurt, as you heard from my colleague Rep Omar, it will hurt our economy, our communities that rely on immigrants, whether it's caring for our our families, teaching our kids, building our homes, and so it's
an honor
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): for me to co-sponsor, yet again, Representative Chu's No Ban Act. I too remember I had just been elected to Congress, my first month in Congress, when I showed up at the SeaTac Airport, and we had to literally stop a plane from leaving the gate.
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): bring it back from the tarmac when it had already left the gate because there were Somali immigrants on that plane who had made the trip over to see their families had valid visas and were being denied that day and so I am proud to help lead this act and also to introduce the companion bill to the No Ban Act today the access to counsel legislation which assures people that they will have access to counsel this was a bill that we introduced with the first
Speaker 1 (higher-pitched voice): the first No Ban Act around the Muslim ban, and I did it with then-Senator, U.S. Senator Kamala Harris, and we will introduce it again today to protect people's rights when they're arriving in this country. We've seen this story before. We know what happens. Pain for families, people's rights violated, chaos, and confusion. We will not allow these blanket bans on entire countries. They are not about national security. They're just about discrimination, plain and simple.